Atlantic Cotton Mills Photographs 6526 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Atlantic Cotton Mills Photographs
1983
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Atlantic Cotton Mills
Historic American Engineering Record.
6526 P
1 folders
1 file folder
Photographs.
Photographs of the Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse taken by Jet Lowe for the 1983 Historic American Engineering Record survey.
10062197
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, October 05, 2017
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 07, 2017
Scope and Contents
Interior and exteriof views of the Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse in Lawrence, Massachusetts. Photographs taken by photographer Jet Lowe.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6526: Atlantic Cotton Mills Records
Architecture--Details; Attics; Boardinghouses; Brickwork; Corridors; Fireplaces; Historic American Engineering Record.; Kitchens; Mantels; Staircases; Windows.; Lawrence (Mass.); Lowe, Jet; Atlantic Cotton Mills.
10062197
- Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, done in 1983 as part of HAER survey (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Image depicts the exterior of one end of the Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse in Lawrence, Mass. 3 1/2-story brick building, with two windows under the roof eave and one window on each floor at each side of the building. Bar located in first floor. See folder 1, item 3 for a view of the building from the front, and folder 1, item 12 for a slightly different angle of this view. 10.25 x 12.75 cm.
    Format: Contact sheets.
  - Item 2: Window inside Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts a window in the Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse in Lawrence, Mass., taken from the inside. Wood frame around window and window seat visible. 10.25 x 12.75 cm.
  - Item 3: Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts the former Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse from the front. 3 1/2-story brick building; two doorways in front; three chimneys; windows on fourth floor (under roof eaves) are boarded up. A bar is located on the first floor in the corner. See folder 1, item 1 for a view of the boardinghouse from the end. 12.75 x 10.25 cm.
  - Item 4: Staircase in Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts a staircase in the former Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse in Lawrence, Mass. Staircase is of wood; front hall floor appears to be linoleum print of some sort; closed door at end of hall. 10.25 x 12.75 cm.
  - Item 5: Kitchen in Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts a room used as a kitchen in the former Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse in Lawrence, Mass. Refrigerator blocks doorway (w/closed door); table and chair to the right; freestanding cabinet to the left. Unknown if this would have been the original kitchen in the boardinghouse. 12.75 x 10.25 cm.
  - Item 6: Fireplace and mantel in Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts a fireplace (boarded up) and mantel in a room in the former Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse in Lawrence, Mass. Closed door to the right of the fireplace/mantel. 12.75 x 10.25 cm.
  - Item 7: Hallway in Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts a narrow hallway in the former Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse in Lawrence, Mass. Closed doors line the hallway. 10.25 x 12.75 cm.
  - Item 8: Attic in Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts the attic in the former Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, an interior area underneath the roof eaves; boarded up window is visible on the right; door (leading to hallway?) is on the left. 12.75 x 10.25 cm.
  - Item 9: Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts the former Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse in Lawrence, Mass. Lawrence Plate and Window Glass Co. building visible to the left; traffic on the street. See folder 1, item 3 for a more direct view of this exterior. 12.75 x 10.25 cm.
  - Item 10: Attic in Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts an attic area in the former Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse in Lawrence, Mass., showing laths without plaster, and boarded up window. 12.75 x 10.25 cm.
  - Item 11: Detail of roofline of Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts a detail of the roofline of the former Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse in Lawrence, Mass. Detail of brickwork visible, following the A-frame of the roof. 12.75 x 10.25 cm.
  - Item 12: Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse, Lawrence, Mass., 1983; Contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Image depicts the exterior of one end of the Atlantic Cotton Mills boardinghouse in Lawrence, Mass. 3 1/2-story brick building, with two windows under the roof eave and one window on each floor at each side of the building. Bar located in first floor. See folder 1, item 3 for a view of the building from the front, and folder 1, item 1 for a slightly different angle of this view. 10.25 x 12.75 cm.